{
	"id": "AWS_MLA-C01",
	"certName": "AWS MLA-C01",
	"categories": [
		{
			"name": "Data ingestion and storage",
			"questions": [
				{
					"question": "Which types of data exists?",
					"answer": "Structure, unstructured and semistructured"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is structured data?",
					"answer": "Data that is organized in a defined manner or schema"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the characteristics of structured data?",
					"answer": "1. Easily aggregable, 2. Organize in rows and columns, 3. Has a consistent structure"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is unstructured data?",
					"answer": "Data that doesn't have a predefined structure or schema"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the characteristics of unstructured data?",
					"answer": "1. Not easily querable without preprocessing, 2. May come in various formats"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is semistructured data?",
					"answer": "Data that is not as organized as structured data but has some level of structure in the form of tags, hierarchies or other patterns"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the characteristics of semistructured data?",
					"answer": "1. Elements might be tagged or categorized in some way, 2. More flexible than structured data but not as chaotic as unstructured data"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the properties of data?",
					"answer": "1. Volume, 2. Velocity, 3. Variety"
				},
				{
					"question": "What volume refers to as a property of data?",
					"answer": "Refers to the amount or size of data that organizations are dealing with at any given time"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the characteristics of volume data property?",
					"answer": "1. May range from gigabytes to petabytes or even more, 2. Challenges in storing, processing, and analyzing high volumes of data"
				},
				{
					"question": "What velocity refers to as a property of data?",
					"answer": "Refers to the speed at which new data is generated, collected and processed"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the characteristics of velocity data property?",
					"answer": "1. High velocity requires real-time or near real-time processing capabilities, 2. Rapid ingestion and processing can be critical for certain applications"
				},
				{
					"question": "What variety refers to as a property of data?",
					"answer": "Refers to the different types, structures and sources of data"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the characteristics of variety data property?",
					"answer": "1. Data can be structured, semistructured and unstructured; 2. Data can come from multiple sources and in various formats"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is a Data warehouse?",
					"answer": "Centralized repository optimized for analysis where data from different sources is stored in a structured format"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the characteristics of a Data warehouse?",
					"answer": "1. Designed for complex queries and analysis; 2. Data is cleaned, transformed and loaded (ETL process); 3. Typically uses a star or snowflake schema; 4. Optimized for read-heavy operations"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is a Data Lake?",
					"answer": "A storage repository that holds vast amounts of raw data in its native format, including structured, semistructured and unstructured data"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the characteristics of a Data Lake?",
					"answer": "1. Can store large volumes of raw data without predefined schema; 2. Data is loaded as-is, no need for preprocessing; 3. Supports batch, real-time and stream processing; 4. Can be queried for data transformation or exploration purposes"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the differences between a Data warehouse and a Data Lake regards schema?",
					"answer": "Data warehouse uses the schema on write model where we have a predefined schema before writing data; Data Lake uses the schema on read model where the schema is defined at the time of reading data"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the differences between a Data warehouse and a Data Lake regards Data types?",
					"answer": "Data warehouse has primarily structured data while data lakes can handle both structured and unstructured data"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the differences between a Data warehouse and a Data Lake regards Agility?",
					"answer": "Data warehouse is less agile due to predefined schema while data lake is more agile as it accepts raw data without predefined structure"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the differences between a Data warehouse and a Data Lake regards Cost?",
					"answer": "Data warehouse is more expensive because of optimization for complex queries while data lake is cost-effective but costs can raise when processing large amounts of data"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is a Data LakeHouse?",
					"answer": "A hybrid data architecture that combines the best features of data lakes and data warehouses, aiming to provide the performance, reliability, and capability of a data warehouse while maintaining the flexibility, scale, and low cost of data lakes"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the characteristics of a Data LakeHouse?",
					"answer": "1. Supports both structured and unstructured data; 2. Allows for schema on write and schema on read; 3. Provides capabilities for both detailed analytics and machine learning tasks; 4. Typically built on top of cloud or distributed architectures; 5. Benefits from technologies like delta-lake"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is a Data mesh about?",
					"answer": "It is about governance and organization, how you structure, access and ownership of data"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is an ETL Pipeline?",
					"answer": "Process used to move data from source systems into a data warehouse"
				},
				{
					"question": "Within an ETL Pipeline, what is Extract about?",
					"answer": "1. Retrieve raw data from source systems; 2. Ensure data integrity during the extraction phase"
				},
				{
					"question": "Within an ETL Pipeline, how can extract be executed?",
					"answer": "Real-time or in batches, depending on requirements"
				},
				{
					"question": "Within an ETL Pipeline, what is Transform about?",
					"answer": "Convert the extracted data into a format suitable for the target data warehouse"
				},
				{
					"question": "Within an ETL Pipeline, what operations can be executed in Transform phase?",
					"answer": "1. Data cleansing; 2. Data enrichment; 3. Format changes; 4. Aggregations or computations; 5. Encoding or decoding data; 6. Handling missing values"
				},
				{
					"question": "Within an ETL Pipeline, what is Load about?",
					"answer": "Move the transformed data into the target data warehouse or another data repository"
				},
				{
					"question": "Within an ETL Pipeline, how can load be executed?",
					"answer": "Batches (all at once) or streaming manner (as data becomes available)"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are some of the file data formats for data engineering?",
					"answer": "1. CSV (Comma-Separated Value); 2. JSON (JavaScript Object Notation); 3. Avro; 4. Parquet"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is CSV?",
					"answer": "Text-based format that represents data in a tabular form where each line corresponds to a row and values within a row are separated by commas"
				},
				{
					"question": "When to use CSV?",
					"answer": "1. For small to medium datasets; 2. Data interchange between systems with different technologies; 3. Human-readable and editable data storage; 4. Importing/Exporting data from databases or spreadsheets"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is JSON?",
					"answer": "Lightweight, text-based, and human-readable data interchange format that represents structured or semistructured data based on key-value pairs"
				},
				{
					"question": "When to use JSON?",
					"answer": "1. Data interchange between a web server and a web client; 2. Configurations and settings for software applications; 3. Use cases that need flexible schema or nested data structures"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Avro?",
					"answer": "Binary format that stores both the data and its schema, allowing it to be processed later with different systems without needing the original system context"
				},
				{
					"question": "When to use Avro?",
					"answer": "1. Big data and real-time processing systems; 2. Schema evolution (Changes in data structure) is needed; 3. Efficient serialization for data transport between systems"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Parquet?",
					"answer": "Columnar storage format optimized for analytics. Allows for efficient compresion and encoding schemas"
				},
				{
					"question": "When to use Parquet?",
					"answer": "1. Analyzing large datasets with analytics engines; 2. Use cases where reading specific columns instead of entire records is beneficial; 3. Storing data on distributed systems where I/O operations and storage need optimization"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are Amazon S3 use cases?",
					"answer": "1. Backup and storage; 2. Disaster recovery; 3. Archive; 4. Hybrid Cloud Storage; 5. Static website; 6. Application hosting; 7. Media hosting; 8. Data lakes and big data analytics; 9. Software delivery"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Amazon S3 Versioning?",
					"answer": "A means of keeping multiple variants of an object in the same bucket"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Amazon S3 Versioning used for?",
					"answer": "To preserve, retrieve, and restore every version of every object stored in your buckets"
				},
				{
					"question": "Within Amazon S3, versinoning is enable at which level?",
					"answer": "Bucket level"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Amazon S3 replication?",
					"answer": "Automatic, asynchronous copying of objects across Amazon S3 buckets"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the prerrequisites for Amazon S3 replication?",
					"answer": "Versioning must be enable in source and destination buckets"
				},
				{
					"question": "What types of Amazon S3 replication do exist?",
					"answer": "1. CRR (Cross-Region Replication); 2. SRR (Same-Region Replication)"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the use case of Amazon S3 CRR?",
					"answer": "Compliance, lower latency access, replication between accounts"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the use case of Amazon S3 SRR?",
					"answer": "Log aggregation, Live replication between production and test accounts"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the S3 storage classes?",
					"answer": "1. Standard - General purpose; 2. Standard - Infrequent access (IA); 3. One zone - Infrequent Access; 4. Glacier Instant Retrieval; 5. Glacier Flexible Retrieval; 6. Glacier Deep Archive; 7. Intelligent Tiering"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Lifecycle management feature within Amazon S3?",
					"answer": "Move files between storage classes after N days"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Amazon EFS?",
					"answer": "Managed NFS (Network File System) that can be mounted on many EC2"
				},
				{
					"question": "How many AZs are used by Amazon EFS?",
					"answer": "EFS works in multi AZ"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the quality attributes covered by Amazon EFS?",
					"answer": "1. Highly available; 2. Scalable; 3. Pay per use"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the use cases of Amazon EFS?",
					"answer": "1. Content management; 2. Web serving; 3. Data sharing; 4. Wordpress"
				},
				{
					"question": "How the access is controlled in Amazon EFS?",
					"answer": "Through security groups"
				},
				{
					"question": "How the access is controlled in Amazon EFS?",
					"answer": "Through security groups"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which AMIs are compatible with Amazon EFS?",
					"answer": "Linux-based AMIs, not windows"
				},
				{
					"question": "How we can use encryption at rest in Amazon EFS?",
					"answer": "Using KMS"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the performance modes of Amazon EFS?",
					"answer": "1. General purpose; 2. Max I/O"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is General purpose performance modes of Amazon EFS used for?",
					"answer": "latency-sensitive use cases"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Max I/O performance modes of Amazon EFS used for?",
					"answer": "Higher latency, throughput, highly parallel"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the throughput modes of Amazon EFS?",
					"answer": "1. Bursting; 2. Provisioned; 3. Elastic"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the characteristics of Bursting thoughput mode of Amazon EFS?",
					"answer": "1 TB = 50 Mb/s + burst of up to 100 Mb/s"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the characteristics of Provisioned thoughput mode of Amazon EFS?",
					"answer": "Set your throughput regardless of storage size"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the characteristics of Elastic thoughput mode of Amazon EFS?",
					"answer": "Automatically scales throughput up or down based on your workloads; Up to 3 Gb/s for reads and 1 Gb/s for writes"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the storage classes of Amazon EFS?",
					"answer": "1. Standard; 2. Infrequent Access; 3. Archive"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Standard storage class of Amazon EFS used for?",
					"answer": "Frequently accessed files"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Infrequent Access storage class of Amazon EFS used for?",
					"answer": "Cost for retrieve files, lower price to store"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Archive storage class of Amazon EFS used for?",
					"answer": "Rarely accessed data (Few times each year), 50% cheaper"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the storage types of Amazon EFS based on availability and durability?",
					"answer": "1. Standard; 2. One zone"
				},
				{
					"question": "How many EC2 instances a single EBS volume can be attached to?",
					"answer": "An EBS volume can be attached to one instance (except multi attach io1/io2)"
				},
				{
					"question": "How many AZs are used by an EBS volume?",
					"answer": "Just one, EBS are locked at AZ level"
				},
				{
					"question": "How IO can be increase in GP2 EBS volumes?",
					"answer": "IO increases if disk size increase"
				},
				{
					"question": "How IO can be increase in GP3 and IO1 EBS volumes?",
					"answer": "IO increases independently"
				},
				{
					"question": "How an EBS volume can be migrated across AZs?",
					"answer": "1. Take a snapshot of the volume; 2. Restore the snapshot to another AZ"
				},
				{
					"question": "What do you need to consider when performing a Backup of an EBS volume?",
					"answer": "Backup use IO and you shouldn't run them while your application is handling a lot of traffic"
				},
				{
					"question": "What happens with root EBS volumes by default if instances get terminated?",
					"answer": "root EBS volumes get terminated as well"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is an instance store?",
					"answer": "Provides temporary block-level storage for your EC2 instances"
				},
				{
					"question": "Where is attach the instance store?",
					"answer": "It is physically attached to the EC2 instance"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Amazon FSx?",
					"answer": "3rd party high performance file system on AWS"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the types of Amazon FSx?",
					"answer": "1. FSx for lustre; 2. FSx for Windows File Server; 3. FSx for NetApp ONTAP; 4. FSx for OpenZFS"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Amazon FSx for Windows?",
					"answer": "Fully managed Windows file system share drive"
				},
				{
					"question": "What protocols are supported by Amazon FSx for Windows?",
					"answer": "1. SMB; 2. Windows NFTS"
				},
				{
					"question": "What instances can be used with Amazon FSx for Windows?",
					"answer": "Linux EC2 instances"
				},
				{
					"question": "What namespaces are supported by Amazon FSx for Windows?",
					"answer": "Distributed File System (DFS) namespaces"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the scalability of Amazon FSx for Windows?",
					"answer": "Up to 10s of GB/s, millions of IOPS, 100PB of data"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the storage options of Amazon FSx for Windows?",
					"answer": "1. SSD; 2. HDD"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the use case of SSD storage option of Amazon FSx for Windows?",
					"answer": "Latency sensitive workloads"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the use case of HDD storage option of Amazon FSx for Windows?",
					"answer": "Broad spectrum of workloads"
				},
				{
					"question": "can Amazon FSx for Windows be accessed from on-premise?",
					"answer": "Yes, through VPN or direct connect"
				},
				{
					"question": "how the backup of Amazon FSx for Windows works?",
					"answer": "It is backed up daily in S3"
				}

			]
		},
		{
			"name": "AWS Managed AI Services",
			"questions": [
				{
					"question": "What are AWS AI managed services?",
					"answer": "Pre-trained ML Services for your use-case"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the main characteristics of AWS AI managed services?",
					"answer": "1. Responsiveness, 2. Availability, 3. Redundancy, 4. Regional coverage"
				},
				{
					"question": "What can we say about performance of AWS AI managed services?",
					"answer": "AWS has specialized CPU and GPU for specific use-cases and cost-savings"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which price models does AWS AI managed services have?",
					"answer": "1. Token-based pricing, 2. Provisioned throughput"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is token-based pricing?",
					"answer": "You pay for what you have used"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is provisioned-throughput used for?",
					"answer": "Predictable workloads, cost savings and predictable performance"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Amazon Comprehend?",
					"answer": "Fully managed and serverless service for Natural Language Processing (NLP)"
				},
				{
					"question": "What Amazon Comprehend uses?",
					"answer": "It uses machine learning to find insights and relationships in text"
				},
				{
					"question": "What Amazon Comprehend does?",
					"answer": "1. Extract language of the text, 2. Extract key phrases, places, people, brands or events, 3. Understand how positive or negative the text is, 4. Analyze text using tokenization and parts of the speech, 5. Automatically organizes a collection of text files by topic"
				},
				{
					"question": "What custom classification does within Amazon Comprehend?",
					"answer": "It organize documents into categories (classes) that you define"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which document types are supported by custom classification within Amazon Comprehend?",
					"answer": "It support text, PDFs, Words and images"
				},
				{
					"question": "Regard velocity, which are the analysis types of custom classification within Amazon Comprehend?",
					"answer": "1. Real-time analysis, 2. Async analysis"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Named Entity Recognition (NER) in Amazon Comprehend?",
					"answer": "Extracts predefined, general purpose entities like people, places, organizations, dates, and other standard categories from text"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Custom Entity Recognition in Amazon Comprehend?",
					"answer": "Analyze text for specific terms, anything specific to your business"
				},
				{
					"question": "What do you provide to train the Custom Entity Recognition model in Amazon Comprehend?",
					"answer": "List of entities and documents that contain them"
				},
				{
					"question": "Regard velocity, which are the analysis types of Custom Entity Recognition model in Amazon Comprehend?",
					"answer": "Real-time or async analysis"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Amazon Translate?",
					"answer": "Natural and accurate language translation"
				},
				{
					"question": "What Amazon Translate allows?",
					"answer": "It allows you to localize content (such as websites and applications) for international users, and to easily translate large volumes of text efficiently"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Amazon Transcribe?",
					"answer": "Service to convert speech to text"
				},
				{
					"question": "What Amazon Transcribe uses?",
					"answer": "It uses a deep learning process called Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) to convert speech to text quickly and accurately"
				},
				{
					"question": "How can we improve the accuracy of Amazon Transcribe?",
					"answer": "Through a custom vocabulary and custom language models"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Amazon Polly?",
					"answer": "Turn text into lifelike speech using deep learning"
				},
				{
					"question": "What Amazon Polly allows?",
					"answer": "It allows you to create applications that talk"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the advanced features of Amazon Polly?",
					"answer": "1. Lexicons, 2. SSML (Speech Synthesis Markup Language), 3. Voice engine, 4. Speech mark"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Lexicons about in Amazon Polly?",
					"answer": "you can modify the pronunciation of particular words, such as company names, acronyms, foreign words and neologisms"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is SSML (Speech Synthesis Markup Language) about in Amazon Polly?",
					"answer": "Tags for phrasing, emphasis, and intonation"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Voice engine about in Amazon Polly?",
					"answer": "Generative, long-form, neural standard"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Speech mark about in Amazon Polly?",
					"answer": "Encode where a sentence/word starts or ends in the audios, helpful for lip-syncing"
				},
				{
					"question": "What Amazon Rekognition does?",
					"answer": "Finds objects, people, text, scenes in images and videos using ML"
				},
				{
					"question": "Regarding faces, what Amazon Rekognition can do?",
					"answer": "Facial analysis and facial search to do user verification and people counting"
				},
				{
					"question": "Against which faces are compared when Amazon Rekognition performs the facial search?",
					"answer": "Celebrities or you can create a database of 'familiar faces'"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the use cases of Amazon Rekognition?",
					"answer": "1. Labeling, 2. Content moderation, 3. Text detection, 4. Face detection and analysis, 5. Face search and verification, 6. Celebrity recognition, 7.Pathing (for sport game analysis)"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is custom label about in Amazon Rekognition?",
					"answer": "Find a specific image in images, ex. find your logo in social media posts, identify your products on store shelves"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the steps to train a custom label about in Amazon Rekognition?",
					"answer": "1. Label your training images and upload them to Amazon Rekognition, 2. Amazon Rekognition creates a custom model on your images set, 3. New subsequent images will be categorized the custom way you have defined"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is content moderation in Amazon Rekognition used for?",
					"answer": "Automatic detection of inappropriate, unwanted or offensive content"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the results of content moderation in Amazon Rekognition?",
					"answer": "Bring down human review to 1-5% of total content volume"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which service can be integrated with Amazon Rekognition for content moderation?",
					"answer": "Amazon Augmented AI (Amazon A2I) for human review"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are custom moderation adaptors used for?",
					"answer": "1. Extend Rekognition capabilities by providing your own labeled set of images, 2. Enhance the accuracy of content moderation or create a specific use case of moderation"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Amazon Forecast?",
					"answer": "Fully managed service that uses ML to deliver highly accurate forecasts"
				},
				{
					"question": "What do you need to perform forecasts in Amazon Forecast?",
					"answer": "Historical time-series data"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Amazon Lex used for?",
					"answer": "It is used for building chatbots quickly for your applications using voice and text"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are some of the possible integrations of Amazon Lex?",
					"answer": "1. AWS Lambda, 2. Connect, 3. Comprehend, 4. Kendra"
				},
				{
					"question": "What the Amazon Lex bot does?",
					"answer": "Understand the user intent to invoke the correct lambda function and fulfill the intent. It will ask for slots (input parameters) if required"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Amazon Personalize?",
					"answer": "Fully managed ML service to build apps with real-time personalized recommendation"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are recipes in Amazon Personalize?",
					"answer": "Algorithms that are prepared for specific use cases, you must provide the training configuration on top of the recipe"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are recipes'' training configurations in Amazon Personalize?",
					"answer": "1. USER_PERSONALIZATION, 2. PERSONALIZED_RANKING, 3. POPULAR_ITEMS, 4. RELATED_ITEMS, 5. PERSONALIZED_ACTION, 6. USER_SEGMENTS"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is USER_PERSONALIZATION training configurations about in Amazon Personalize?",
					"answer": "Recommend items for users"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is PERSONALIZED_RANKING training configurations about in Amazon Personalize?",
					"answer": "Ranks items for a user"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is POPULAR_ITEMS training configurations about in Amazon Personalize?",
					"answer": "Recommend trending or popular items"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is RELATED_ITEMS training configurations about in Amazon Personalize?",
					"answer": "Recommend similar items"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is PERSONALIZED_ACTION training configurations about in Amazon Personalize?",
					"answer": "Recommend the next best action"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is USER_SEGMENTS training configurations about in Amazon Personalize?",
					"answer": "Get the user segment"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Amazon Textract?",
					"answer": "Automatically extracts text, handwriting, and data from any scanned documents using AI and ML"
				},
				{
					"question": "Where can Amazon Textract extract data from?",
					"answer": "It can extrat data from forms and tables"
				},
				{
					"question": "What type of documents can Amazon Textract extract data from?",
					"answer": "PDFs, images, etc"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Amazon Kendra?",
					"answer": "Fully managed document search service powered by Machine Learning"
				},
				{
					"question": "What Amazon Kendra does?",
					"answer": "It extracts answers from within a document though Natural Language search capabilities"
				},
				{
					"question": "What type of documents can Amazon Kendra searc information from?",
					"answer": "Text, PDF, HTML, PowerPoint, MS Word, FAQs, etc."
				},
				{
					"question": "What is incremental learning in Amazon Kendra?",
					"answer": "Learn from user interactions/feedback to promote preferred results"
				},
				{
					"question": "What Amazon Augmented AI provides?",
					"answer": "Human oversight of Machine Learning predictions in production"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the predictions of a model according to Amazon Augmented AI?",
					"answer": "High confidence and low confidence predictions"
				},
				{
					"question": "Where can be the model which Amazon Augmented AI can check?",
					"answer": "ML model can be built on AWS or elsewhere"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the EC2 instances with GPU?",
					"answer": "P and G family"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is AWS Trainium?",
					"answer": "ML chip built to perform Deep Learning on 100B+ parameter models"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the saving in cost of using AWS Trainium?",
					"answer": "50% cost reduction when training a model"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is AWS Inferentia?",
					"answer": "ML chip built to deliver inference at high performance and low cost"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is benefits of using AWS Inferentia?",
					"answer": "Up to 4x throughput and 70% cost reduction"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Amazon Lookout?",
					"answer": "Service to detect and diagnose anomalies"
				},
				{
					"question": "What are the types of unusual variances Amazon Lookout checks?",
					"answer": "1. Business performance, 2. Ad campaigns, 3. Whatever"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the main components on Amazon Lookout?",
					"answer": "1. Detectors, 2. Datasets, 3. Anomalies"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are the specialized version for industries of Amazon Lookout?",
					"answer": "1. For equipment: integrate with equipment sensors for predictive maintenance, 2. For vision: automate quality inspection with computer vision"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Amazon Fraud Detector?",
					"answer": "Fully managed ML model customized to your data for fraud detection"
				},
				{
					"question": "How can we feed Amazon Fraud Detector?",
					"answer": "From S3 or API"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is Amazon Q Business?",
					"answer": "Fully managed Gen-AI assistant for your employees"
				},
				{
					"question": "What Amazon Q Business can do?",
					"answer": "based on your company's knowledge and data: 1. Answer questions, provide summaries, generate content, automate tasks; 2. Perform routine activities"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is the foundation service of Amazon Q Business?",
					"answer": "Amazon BedRock, you cna't choose the the underlying Foundation Model"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is a data connector of Amazon Q Business?",
					"answer": "Fully managed RAG"
				},
				{
					"question": "How many data sources are supported by Amazon Q Business data connectors?",
					"answer": "Connects to 40+ popular enterprise data sources"
				},
				{
					"question": "What is a Amazon Q Business plugin?",
					"answer": "Allows you to interact with 3rd party services like Jira, ServiceNow or custom plugins (APIs)"
				},
				{
					"question": "How is Authentication and Authorization managed in Amazon Q Business?",
					"answer": "Authentication - Users must be authenticated through IAM Identity Center; Authorization - Users receive responses generated only from the documents they have access to"
				},
				{
					"question": "Which are some of the admin controls of Amazon Q Business?",
					"answer": "1. Controls and customize responses to your organizational needs; 2 Guardrails; 3. Block specific words or topics; 4. Choose between respond only with internal information vs using external knowledge"
				},
				{
					"question": "What can you do with Amazon Q Apps?",
					"answer": "Create Gen AI-powered apps wiothout coding by using natural language"
				},
				{
					"question": "What can you do with Amazon Q Developer?",
					"answer": "1. Answer questions about AWS documentation and AWS services selection, also about resources in your AWS account; 2. AI code compension to help you to code new application"
				}
			]
		}
	]
}